hi and welcome to living in Central
Texas if you are relocating to the
Temple Texas area belon Bell County or
any of the surrounding areas you'll
probably want to check out this video if
you're considering new construction
today we'll be touring Deer Grove it's
just on the outskirts of Temple Texas
it's in Moffet Temple addresses but Bel
and ISD super confusing I know but
that's what I'm here for um so there are
are a bunch of really beautiful homes in
here and I can't wait to show you hi I'm
Andrea dudic realtor and Associate
Brooker with Vista Real Estate this is a
great Community if you're looking for
low property taxes we're outside of City
Limits here so you're going to save some
money there all of the lots are very
large for this price point they're about
a half acre and the current price points
are just under 500,000 up to 600,000 but
a lot of these homes are actually
appraising for $100,000 more than
they're currently selling for how
awesome right well let's go take a look
so before we get started I actually
wanted to give you a little idea of
location so this community is off of um
36 it's about 35 minutes from Fort
Cavazos 45 minutes from Waco and an hour
and 15 minutes from Austin so location
is really great here because of State
Highway 36 and just easy jumping on and
off of all the freeways the the first
home that we'll be taking a look at
behind me is bright side Builders I
actually hadn't heard of this Builder
before but it was really cute when I
took a look so I thought it'd be a good
one to look at today it is 2300 is
square ft four bed 2 and 1/2 bath on a
half acre lot and they are currently
asking
537 now again a lot of these homes are
going far below apprais value really
great opport Unity to get into your next
home with some Instant Equity let's take
a look so one of the things I really
love about Texas is the exterior of the
homes which they call the elevation
there's a lot of detail that goes into
the stone and stucco work which I guess
isn't everywhere um and I just really
think that that makes the aesthetic and
exterior of the home look really nice so
without further Ado let's check out
number one bright side
homes now as we walk in you can see they
have a really pretty entry chandelier
they went with the um blond light
colored vinyl plank flooring throughout
the
home with dark accents so all of our
cabinets are painted dark in this home
in particular they do have propane so
not common to Texas or at least in
Central Texas is gas natural gas is in
some of the some of the communities but
if that's something that's important to
you you definitely want to check when
looking into your new home this one has
been set up with propane so the
fireplace we have a really pretty brick
fireplace with builtins on each side
painted black I think that looks really
pretty and everything
opens really
nicely uh the first thing I noticed when
I walked into this house was actually
this
window so this space is so pretty I
think this is really the center focal
point or the focal point of the entire
home you have this beautiful builtin bar
area um for China or you know coffee
liquor whatever you want but it's really
pretty big uh dining table
here you have your quartz
countertops gas rain
huge seller um two toned cabinets gray
with your I think this is actually like
a dark blue when the lights hitting it
and oh they even alternated their
Hardware so some is black and some is
gold that's pretty
cool but lots of Windows and Lighting in
this home recess lighting pendant
lighting I think they did a really great
job of making sure it felt really bright
in here which makes sense bright side
homes
sliding glass door to your exterior
looks like there's a really large
covered patio out
there and let's keep taking a look
inside so this home actually has a split
floor plan we'll start with the um main
bedroom really high vaed ceilings
I noticed there's no carpet in this home
so if that's important to you that's
really great with this with this one um
huge bathroom hexagon tile
floor you have his and her or dual
vanity
sinks soaking tub and a huge walk-in
shower with two shower
heads and then a really awesome walk-in
closet with a built-in
dresser another little Minor Detail is
floor
plugs I guess as I get older I start to
think that that's really cool and almost
fell over really cool and functional is
the floor plugs you know if you want to
put a put a light or a end table
there now this side of the home are your
other bedrooms and bath your secondary
bath again dual
vanity shower tub
combo and then your remaining three
bedrooms
so let's head on over to the laundry
room and
garage so here's your half bath right
off the main living space so then no one
has to go into the bedroom space you
also have a mud bench that's really
pretty and then a really great sized l
laundry
room I think this is just
storage
yes okay well what I really like about
this house again feels super bright open
Airy my only dislike really I actually
don't love pointing out this sort of
stuff but my only real dislike is that
it doesn't have a pantry and I do
generally feel that buyers prefer a
house of this size to have a
pantry so nice oversized extended
patio pretty
wood
ceiling and just a really large flat
backyard all of the homes out here are
on
septic it's pretty common especially
with the larger properties but this was
number one we'll go take a look at two
others and see which one's your
favorite okay stop number two this is a
Robinson home new construction it is
four bed two bath
2457 ft priced at
$4.95 it is such a good price for this
comb um again on a half acre let's go
take a look the outside of this comb is
super inviting it has this beautiful
Arch entryway with the it's a natural
stone I thought that looked really
pretty little front porch to put rocking
chairs or whatever you want and the
double entry
door nice little detail they also have
Herring
bone entry like which is the style of
that wood like tile that is ceramic that
is ceramic tile um which is really
pretty and a nice little upgrade so this
home is about 100 ft more than the last
one we looked at but to me it feels like
there's more space they did a really
good job in functionality uh of this
layout so when we walk into the home it
does have more of a I would say rustic
feel to it um more of the warmer tones
on this side of the home it's really
cool you have these French door do that
open into a office area or flex room
with the recessed lighting and wood
beam another little thing to note is
that this Builder included blinds the
last one did not so on this side we have
a formal dining
space which also leads into the kitchen
there and we'll circle
around but our entryway leads into your
main living space with coffered
ceilings wood beams with the uh recess
lighting there also really pretty stone
fireplace this home does not have gas it
is
electric but you have a little eaten
kitchen area if you want to have
breakfast or just smaller
Gatherings your kitchen opens into the
living room but this is actually granite
countertops and Custom Cabinets these
are really
pretty oh this is cute I don't see this
very often
anymore so we have electric
appliances
frigider for
all and then over here we have your
laundry
room with a utility sink and then it
leads into the garage uh two-car
garage so I'd say the last home was more
open um this one still feels pretty open
but I think they just utilized the space
to put more um areas in utility
closet now the walls in
here they're they're gray but they have
like a green undertone I would I would
say again you have your trade ceilings
make the room feel a little bit bigger
with with the additional recess lighting
and this cute accent accented wood
paneling we do have carpet throughout
the main I'm sorry throughout of the
bedrooms dual
vanity you have a soaking tub and a
walk-in
shower lots of Gray Storage
and your separate
commode the carpets are
gray a really great size walk-in
closet and again another split floor
plan but even all the light fixtures
super rustic
totally different feel from the last
home and then on the side of the home
you have two
bedrooms
that share
the
bathroom so let's go take a look at the
backyard
so this one is a half acre but I think
the last one felt a little bit bigger at
the
backyard and a little bit more private
but still really
[Music]
cute so youve about a $40,000 price
point in the two boat very beautiful
both very
different we have one more let's go go
this is the last of our three homes this
is Circle G homes it is 2700 Square ft
four bed 3 and 1/2 bath so super large
and it does have one bed um upstairs so
really interesting how this one is laid
out again lots of space it is the most
expensive of all the homes that we have
looked at which reflects which is
reflected in that price per square foot
but um originally 600 19,000 now
$5.99 and again another really different
but really beautiful home I've been
really excited to show you this home it
is a traditional style home um but the
outside has a reddish dark red brick and
uh White Austin Limestone on the front
with these big beautiful cedar posts and
front porch um the outside is cute but
the inside is even prettier
let's
go so when you walk in I think the first
thing to note is the just detail of the
paneling the wood paneling and the light
fixtures it just feels super elegant and
Polished when you walk
in and then you have these really
beautiful sliding
doors they did a sage green accent
throughout the home um but this could be
your formal dining space office you
again have coford ceilings with recess
lighting really beautiful
Chandelier the main living space is so
inviting um you have your red brick to
match the exterior of the home really
pulling the out
in this home does have gas as well the
uh
propane I think they did a awesome job
of doing you you know bringing in some
of these natural
elements but you have white hortz
countertops I think this is just pretend
this is green I think that was just an
accident but uh really
beautiful
um textured backsplash with gold accents
you have your gold pot filler so pretty
tons of cabinet space stainless steel
appliances little details like your
spice rack your pull out spice rack they
already say dual oven dual oven
microwave and then this one does not
have a pantry either but it does have
again a lot of cabinet
space and I think this will probably
serve as a pantry it's what they were
going for they did great with the gold
and white white toned pendants above the
island carrying it through in the
chandelier in the formal dining
space and the best part of
this I
think how beautiful is this wet bar
area just super great for hosting or
hanging hanging out solo whatever you
prefer we have vinyl plank flooring
throughout
the entire home I don't think there's
any carpet
here um upstairs which we'll go upstairs
in a minute we have one bath and one
bed down here we have two more secondary
bedrooms and a really funky little
bathroom the tile I think is super
fun really great oversized walk-in
closets for secondary
bedrooms and then this little Nook from
underneath the stairs they put a little
light there um I just pictured a little
tiny kid desk or something I don't know
a doggy space let's go
upstairs okay so up here you really just
this is a really awesome opportunity to
do um if you're looking to host or
someone needing a little bit more
privacy they kind of have their own
little living quarters up
here and then the really pretty
bathroom with great cabinets again that
stage green accent looks like granite
countertops and let's head back down now
what I'm really loving about this
neighborhood is that it's I do love
production Builders don't get me wrong
like they have great sister they have
great floor plans and they have
beautiful homes but what's really unique
about this community is that there are
so many different Builders and you can
see the different styles and detail that
they put into each of their homes okay
let's head on over to the primary
bedroom but first this is your half bath
off of O this is your half bath off of
the main living spaces and this is the
primary bedroom super beautiful um tray
ceiling with a pop up you have an
electric
fireplace in your
bedroom lots of lighting into the
backyard vinyl plank in here as well
leading into your uh primary Suite bath
Suite dual vanity all of the gold
finishes soaking tub with a beautiful
Chandelier above it and how pretty is
that
shower you have the rain fall shower
head and a ginormous
closet we've seen this in a couple homes
now um I feel like this is a new thing
that Builders have started doing again
but I really like it adding in the
dresser in the closets pretty cool
and last but not least we're going to
head outside to the backyard on this one
so again this was the highest priced
home out of everything that we've seen
today but again much larger square
footage than everything that we've seen
and I think there are some um upgrades
in this one that are not
standard again one being the gas the
propane before we head to the back yard
let's check out the laundry
room when you walk in through the garage
you have your mud room with your mud
bench pull out drawers under there is
super clever a lot of times you put
baskets there and they get kind of just
full of junk but that was a great idea
little folding station or Prep Station
in the laundry room with the cabinets
above really
pretty I think this layout is really
functional
can carry your groceries straight in
from the garage into the
kitchen and last but not
least the back patio on number three
with the
fireplace I think this is an awesome
space for entertaining and hanging out
um you have a lot of space to do with in
the backyard and overall I just think
all of these homes are really fantastic
and a good fit for someone I mean I
think there's a home for everyone here I
really hope you enjoyed this tour today
of Deer Grove within the temple Moffet
area if you have any questions you can
find all my contact information below
don't forget to subscribe so that you
can stay up toate on all things living
in Central Texas
[Music]